Brett Henderson

Curriculum Vitae

February 2021

: Department of Chemistry, University of Victoria.

\ : +1 (760) 807-4785\ : bhenderson@uvic.ca\ : brettrhenderson.github.io

?: github.com/brettrhenderson

in: www.linkedin.com/in/brettrhenderson

Summary

I am a computational chemist interested in simulating nature with the best available computational technologies. My current research involves ab initio molecular dynamics simulations of solid-state materials and my passion is computational method development. My hope and vision is to help design the algorithms and software for studying the materials of the future.

Education

2013-2017	A.B. Engineering Sciences—Electrical and Computer Engi-	Harvard University
	neering (Cum Laude in Field), Secondary Computer Science	
2019-present	Ph.D. Student in Chemistry	University of Victoria

Research Experience

2019-present Ph.D. Student, Paci Group University of Victoria

My research focus is simulating the dielectric response of nanocomposite materials both from first principles using density functional theory and through coarse-grained models based on classical electrostatics and the finite element method in MATLAB®.

2016–2017 Research Assistant, Vecitis Lab Harvard University

I fabricated reduced graphene oxide supercapacitors using a combination of bench-top and clean room techniques and helped characterize the devices using cyclic voltammetry and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy.

Employment History

2017–2018 Emerging Technologies Systems Engineer The MITRE Corporation

I worked primarily as a python programmer and developed a tool leveraging optical character recognition and natural language processing to help automate quality assurance testing of captioned telephones. In another project, I helped build an extension of a Windows-based automated cybersecurity red-teaming software for use on Linux machines.

Honors and Awards

2021	1st Prize, Poster Contest, QSciTech-QuantumBC Virtual Workshop: Gate-based QC
2016, 2017	All-Academic Men's Track and Field Team, All-Academic Board of the National Colle-
	giate Division 1 Track and Field Coaches Association
2017	Academic All-America Third Team, College Sports Information Directors of America
2015	Harvard College Scholarship Award
2014	John Harvard Award, Harvard College
2014	Detur Book Prize, Harvard College

Grants and Scholarships

2020-2021	Quantum Computing NSERC CREATE program scholarship	\$10,000
Dec. 2020	Mohamed and Prabha Ibrahim Graduate Scholarship in Chemistry	\$1,080
Aug. 2020	Graduate Award - Research Achievement, University of Victoria	\$1,367.33
2019-2020	Graduate Award - Academic Achievement, University of Victoria	\$1,500 biannually
2019	UVic Fellowship	\$10,000

Teaching

- 2021 **Teaching Assistant**, Chem477, Computational Chemistry
- 2020 Teaching Assistant, Chem 347, Quantum Chemistry
- 2020 Laboratory Teaching Assistant, Chem 260, Synthetic Chemistry Laboratory
- 2020 **Tutorial Instructor**, Chem 102, Chemical Reactivity Fundamentals with Environmental Applications
- 2019 Laboratory Teaching Assistant, Chem 150, Engineering Chemistry

Publications

Editorials

1. McFarlane, J., B. Henderson, S. Donnecke, and J. Scott McIndoe (2019a). An information-rich graphical representation of catalytic cycles. *Organometallics* **38**(21).

Public Lectures

1. Henderson, B. (Nov. 2020b). "Playing Dice With the Universe: Harnessing the Weird Behaviour of Quantum Bits to Solve Real World Problems". Nerd Nite Victoria.

Poster Presentations

- 1. Henderson, B., I. Benek-Lins, and M. Mathews (Feb. 2021). "H2 ground state finder using Qiskit". QSciTech-QuantumBC Virtual Workshop: Gate-based Quantum Computing Using IBM Q.
- 2. Henderson, B. (Nov. 2020a). "Coarse-Grained Modeling of nanoComposite Dielectrics". University of Victoria dept. of chemistry graduate student research day poster session.
- 3. Henderson, B., A. Adluri, and I. Paci (Mar. 2020). "Multi-scale modeling of polarization in metal oxide nanocomposites". University of Victoria Ideafest getting up to speed with nature's imagination.
- 4. Henderson, B., A. Adluri, and I. Paci (Nov. 2019). "Multi-scale modeling of polarization in metal oxide nanocomposites". University of Victoria dept. of chemistry graduate student research day poster session.
- 5. McFarlane, J., B. Henderson, S. Donnecke, and J. Scott McIndoe (May 2019b). "An information-rich graphical representation of catalytic cycles". Inorganic Discussion Weekend, University of Victoria.

Software

These software projects are on display at brettrhenderson.github.io

- 1. Henderson, B. (2020d). "pyFractals". Animation of sierpinski triangle construction via binary tree method. https://github.com/brettrhenderson/pyFractals.
- 2. Henderson, B. (2020e). "PySims". A collection of classical mechanics simulations using python. https://github.com/brettrhenderson/PySims.
- 3. Henderson, B., J. MacFarlane, and S. Donnecke (2019). "Catacycle". An information-rich graphical representation of catalytic cycles. https://github.com/brettrhenderson/Catacycle.
- 4. Sun, A., N. Cable, and B. Henderson (2013). "Pacman: revenge of blinky". CS50 final project. https://github.com/brettrhenderson/pacboi.